没人相信爱丽丝
No one believed Alice
所说的仙境冒险
when she spoke of her adventures in Wonderland,
她是如何爱上了精灵塞勒斯
of how she fell in love with a genie named Cyrus,
-红心王后又是如何拆散了他们  -不
- and how the Red Queen tore them apart. - No!
她被关进了精神病院
She was locked away in an asylum.
爱丽丝  她需要帮助
Alice. She needs help.
所以红桃杰克和我带她回了仙境
So the Knave of Hearts and I brought her back to Wonderland
寻找她的真爱
to search for her true love.
他在这里  我能感觉到
He's here. I can feel it.
有人想阻止她
There are those who will try to stop her.
让那个女孩许下三个愿
What we want can't be accomplished
我们的目的才能达成
until the girl's made all her wishes.
但是爱丽丝的伟大冒险
But Alice's greatest adventure
才刚刚开始
has just begun.
多年前  阿格拉巴
有什么能效劳的
Can I help you?
很快就能知道了
We shall soon find out.
你是法西・沙麦德
You are Farzeen Shahmed?
在市集上卖围巾
You work in the marketplace selling scarves.
对
Yes.
您想买一条吗
Uh... would you like one?
我能挑挑吗
May I?
你赚的钱很少
You earn very little income,
但家里还真是设备齐全
and yet your home is well-appointed.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这不是恭维  而是我亲眼所见的而已
It was not a compliment, but an observation.
你花园里种了大量新鲜蔬菜
You have a bounty of fresh vegetables in your garden,
我还发现你家外面有两头骆驼
and I couldn't help noticing you have two camels outside.
阿格拉巴甚至很少有人能买得起一头
Few men in Agrabah can afford even one.
而你  却有两头
And yet here you are... with two.
我很幸运
I have been very fortunate.
确实如此
Indeed.
看来你拥有一个人所希望的一切
It seems you have everything a man could possibly wish for.
也许你遇见了能赠与愿望的人
Perhaps you've met someone who could grant them.
那些愿望
Wishes.
我不知道你在说什么
I am not sure what you mean.
我的财富是源于家族投资
My good fortune is... due to a family investment
现在终于财源滚滚了
that has finally begun to pay off.
是这样吗
Is that so?
对
Yes.
我还能更解释得跟详细些
I can explain further, if you'll
但我得先去关掉炉子
allow me to turn off the stove.
好啊
Yes.
当然  水烧过了就不好了
Yes. We wouldn't want you to overcook water.
去吧
Go on.
精灵
Genie.
我的主人  你的愿望就是我的愿望
Master mine, my will is thine.
他来了  你说的那个人
He's here! The one you spoke of.
拿着毒蛇杖的人
The man with the serpent staff.
别紧张  他要找的不是你
Steady. It's not you he's after.
我的第三个愿望  我现在就要实现它
My third wish! I want it now.
耐心点  我能帮助你
Have patience. I can help you.
-我希望你消失  -不要
- I wish you gone! - Don't!
远远离开阿格拉巴  就像地球远离太阳
As far from Agrabah as the earth from the sun!
不
No!
你把他送到哪里去了
Where did you send him?
我不知道
I don't know!
求你了
Please!
你想要什么
What is it you desire?
饶我一命
Just... mercy!
那么
Well, then...
看来今天我俩都不能
it seems neither of us are going to get
如愿以偿了
what we want today.
我在哪
Where am I?
什么鬼东西
What the bloody hell?
很好  你醒了
Good. You're up.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我在做准备
I'm getting ready.
我的技艺有些生疏了
I'm a bit rusty.
好了  你把树刺伤了
There. Now you've gone and hurt the tree.
高兴了吧
Happy?
找回了塞勒斯  我才会高兴
I'll be happy once we get Cyrus back.
我们得走了
We need to get moving.
我们在仙境待了太长时间
We've been in Wonderland for too long.
敌人会发现我们的
Our enemies know we're here.
"敌人"  那会是谁
"Our enemies"? Who would they be?
好问题  来吧
Excellent question. Come on.
我有个计划  杰克
I have a plan, Knave.
还有一身新衣服
And a new outfit.
从哪弄来的
Where'd you get that?
晾衣架经过了
The clotheshorse came by.
当然啦
Of course it did.
我们最大的问题是不知道塞勒斯在哪
Our biggest problem is we don't know where Cyrus is.
他可能被困在某地了  或者被抓住了
He could be trapped somewhere, or--or captured.
咖啡架有没有可能经过啊
Look, is there any chance of a coffee horse coming by?
-我没法思考  直到...  -然后我意识到
- I can't really think until-- - But then I realized
我们不需要知道他在哪里
we don't need to know where he is.
-不需要吗  -因为我们知道一件
- Oh, we don't? - Because we know something.
别人都不知道的事
Something nobody else does.
我们知道瓶子藏在哪
We know where the bottle is hidden.
看来你不知道"我们"这词是什么意思
I'm not sure you're clear on what the word "We" means.
这是两步式计划  第一步  我们找到瓶子
It's a two-step plan. Step one--we find the bottle.
第二部  我们许三个无害的愿望
Step two--we make three harmless wishes,
不管他在哪  他就会被收回瓶子里
and no matter where he is, he'll just get drawn back inside.
我记得你说过没有什么
I thought you said there's no such thing
无害的愿望
as a harmless wish.
对  那是对大愿望而言
True. That's if you wish for something big.
但如果你许下某些微不足道的小愿望
But if you wish for something small and innocent,
比如要个纸杯蛋糕  那应该没事
like a cupcake, it should be fine.
这就要说到你了
Which, um, brings us to you.
终于来了
Here it comes.
你要摩擦瓶子
You'll rub the bottle,
塞勒斯就会重新出现  我们就可以再在一起了
and Cyrus will reappear, and we'll be together again.
然后我们再想办法
And then we'll figure out a way to truly free him
让他永远自由
once and for all.
爱丽丝  如果我擦了瓶子
Um, Alice, once I rub the bottle,
那塞勒斯不就是我的精灵了吗
doesn't that make Cyrus my genie?
看来我只得相信你了
I guess I'll just have to trust you.
那好吧
Right then.
我们去哪找这瓶子
Where do we find this bottle?
我们把它埋在了高耸弦树的
We buried it in the Mimsy Meadows,
密草地下
under the towering TumTum Tree.
没人会去那里
It's a place where nobody goes.
取了这种名字  谁会去啊
With a name like that, why would they,
除非是爱心熊
unless they were a care bear?
爱心熊是什么
What's a care bear?
当我没说
Never mind.
你来叫醒他还是我来
You want to wake him or should I?
让他睡吧  可怜的兔子够累的了
Leave him be. Poor Rabbit's been through enough.
其实爱丽丝的意思就是  他拖了我们后退
Which is Alice-speak for "He's slowing us down."
走吧  杰克
Come on, Knave.
该去找瓶子了
Time to get the bottle.
该去找塞勒斯了
Time to get Cyrus.
爱丽丝
Alice?
怎么了  你没事吧
What's going on over there? You all right?
一个一个说
One at a time.
女王陛下要你们遵守秩序
Her majesty demands order.
供水快断了
The water supply's running out.
我的庄稼快死了
My crops are dying!
请您帮帮我们
Please, help us!
亲爱的子民  跟你们说实话吧
Darlings, can I be honest with you?
你们的问题很无聊
Your problems bore me.
亲爱的贾法尔
Dear Jafar...
现身吧  不管你在哪里
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
不知道你怎么忍受得了这些人的
I don't know how you can stand to listen to them,
日复一日
day in, day out.
我是女王
I'm the queen.
这是我的职责
It's my job.
这是你的弱点  你想赢得他们的尊敬
It's your flaw. You were trying to earn their respect.
但你需要做的只是强占
All you have to do is take it.
我夺来了这王冠和仙境
I took this throne. I took wonderland.
但你还是不满足  对吧
And yet, still it's not enough, is it?
要是咱俩之中有一个人满足于现状
I think if either of us were satisfied with what we already had,
又怎么会去跟
we wouldn't be messing about
爱丽丝和她的精灵纠缠呢
with Alice and her genie, now, would we?
要是你不能帮我找到瓶子
If you can't find that bottle for me,
也许这一切都是浪费时间
then maybe this is just a waste of time.
事实上  我才更担心
Actually, I am more concerned whether it is you
名不副实的人是你
who can do what you say you can.
有了精灵瓶子的力量
With the bottle's power,
你是否就真能改变魔法的法则
will you indeed be able to change the laws of magic?
为了化不可能
To make the impossible...
为可能
possible,
你必须有些邪恶的渴望
you must have some truly unholy desires.
我有
Oh, that I do.
你能做到吗
Can you do it?
当然
Of course.
但我们现在还没拿到瓶子
But this talk is foolishly premature
一切都言之尚早
until we have the bottle.
别再在这些农民身上浪费时间了
So why don't you stop wasting time with these peasants
集中精神完成眼下的任务
and focus on the task at hand?
不管我喜不喜欢  我始终是女王  贾法尔
Whether I like it or not, Jafar, I am the queen.
我肩上承担着责任
I have responsibilities.
好了
There.
我已经帮你把今天空出来了
I've cleared your day.
找到精灵的瓶子
Now find the bottle
我就能让爱丽丝许愿了
so I can get Alice to make those wishes...
你也可以用琴声好好收拾她了
And you can have your tweedles sweep her up, too.
继续找  好吗
Keep up, would you?
现在干得不错
We're making good time.
照这速度下去
If we keep at this pace,
中午之前就能到密草地了
we'll arrive at Mimsy Meadows before midday.
你还是小点声吧
You may want to lower your voice.
这里隔墙有耳  是真的耳朵
The walls in this place have ears--literally.
这里的墙都长了耳朵
There are walls with actual ears.
你不会想让整个仙境都知道你要去哪的
You don't want all of wonderland to know where we're going.
当然
Of course not.
你在想  如果我们找到了他该怎么办
You're thinking about what happens if we find him?
一定会找到他
When.
一定会
When we find him.
要是跟你想的不一样呢
What if it's nothing like you thought?
什么意思
Meaning?
我只是想保护你
Well... I just think to protect yourself,
你得考虑到这种可能性
you should consider the possibility
现实也许跟你想的不同
that things may be different.
你离开了很久
You've been gone a long time.
塞勒斯在等我  他需要我
Cyrus is waiting for me. He needs me.
那他为什么不联系你
Then why hasn't he contacted you?
要是你知道他在哪  那他也一定知道你在哪
If you know where he is, surely he knows where you are, too.
他不联系我唯一的理由
The only reason he hasn't contacted me
就是他有麻烦了
is because he must be in trouble.
所以我们得抓紧
That's why we need to pick up the pace.
也许他已经重新开始了
Or he's moved on.
不可能  我和塞勒斯之间...
Not a chance. What Cyrus and I have--
说了你也不明白
Well, you wouldn't understand.
是啊  我是不明白
No. I suppose I wouldn't.
没什么能阻挡我们在一起
Nothing will get in the way of us being together.
除了这个
Except possibly this.
用力
Harder.
再用力
用力
Harder!
兔子
Bunny!
有什么消息
What news do you have for me?
一切都如您所料  按部就班地进行着
Everything is moving along as you predicted.
他们今早离开  去找精灵的瓶子了
They left this morning to get the genie's bottle.
那你知道瓶子在哪了
So you know where it is then.
我...
Uh, I, uh...
要我提醒你欺骗我的后果吗
Need I remind you of the consequences if you lie to me?
不用了  我知道瓶子在哪
Uh, no. Uh... I know exactly where it is.
我们应该能游过去
I suppose we could swim across.
不行
No, we can't.
要是你担心水下有什么危险
If you're afraid of dangers
我可以处理...
lurking beneath the surface, I can handle--
我不会游泳
I can't swim.
你怎么可能这辈子都没...
How have you lived your whole life and never--
-我在忙其它事  -比如呢
- I was doing other things. - Like what?
比如怕水  爱丽丝
Like being afraid of water, Alice.
好吧  那我们等摆渡吧
Fine. We'll just have to wait for the ferry.
有个更好的主意  走过去
Or--better idea-- we walk...
绕道而行
We walk around it.
绕过整个湖
Walk around the entire thing?
那至少要花两天
That would take two days at least.
我们摆渡过去
We're taking the ferry.
她来了
There she is.
在这儿呢  仙女
Over here, fairy.
我是水仙子  你们要...
I am the Fairy Silvermist. Where may I...
我...
I...
你好啊  小水
Hey, Silv.
最近怎么样
How's it going?
-好了  -你俩  认识吧
- There it is. - I take it you two... know each other.
你还敢在仙境露面啊
Awfully bold of you to show your face in wonderland.
你知道有多少人在找你吗
Do you know how many people are looking for you?
好不如去数数有多少人不在找我
Might be easier to figure out how many aren't.
很好笑吗
You think you're funny?
我认为  不管我现在说什么都没用
I think I'm buggered no matter what I say right now.
也许你俩可以在
Perhaps you two might continue reminiscing
我们渡河的时候再叙旧
while we make our way across the lake.
看来我们只能走过去了
I think we have to walk.
不  我很乐意送你们过去
Not at all. I'm happy to take you.
我们俩吗  真的吗
The both of us? Are you sure?
当然  这是我的职责  我很专业
Of course. It's my job, and I'm a professional.
不会让私人感情影响工作
I don't let feelings get in the way of my work,
尤其是那些早已不上心的旧感情
especially old feelings that I've completely moved on from.
好吧  非常感谢
Okay. Thank you very much.
是啊  非常感谢
Yeah, thank you very much.
非常好  我们要去
Excellent. Well, then we need to
高耸弦树下的密草地
get to The Tumtum Tree in Mimsy Meadows.
干嘛  我要告诉她我们的去向
What? I need to tell her where we're going.
别担心  你可以相信我
Don't worry. You can trust me.
我是来帮忙的
I'm here to help.
你被棒子打到的烙印
That burn you got from the bars--
我现在开始明白
I'm starting to understand
为什么只有你的笼子是用银制成的
why yours is the only cage made of silver.
是为了防止你逃跑吗
Is that to keep you from escaping?
是为了杜绝我有逃跑的想法
It's to keep me from even thinking of escaping.
精灵和银器  我们很不合
Genies and silver-- we don't mix.
也许我们可以让你忘却痛苦
Perhaps we can take your mind off the pain.
上次下的是
Last move
车上D3
was rook to D3.
老人家抱歉  我今天不能和你玩
Sorry, old man. I can't play with you today.
你还有更重要的事做吗
You have something better to do?
是的
Yes.
还真的有
Actually... I do.
我亲爱的小姐  你的愿望就是我的愿望
Mistress mine, my will is thine.
打开你的手
Open your hand.
-什么  -你的手  打开看看
- What? - Your hand. Open it.
这些是什么
What are these?
它们是你的愿望
They're your wishes.
好漂亮
Ah, they're so pretty.
你也很漂亮
As are you.
忘记我了吗
Forget about me?
抱歉  兔子
Oh. Sorry, Rabbit.
没有不舒服吧
No hard feelings?
没有  都是我的错
No, I suppose it's my fault.
我从一开始就不该把你带来
I never should have led you down here in the first place.
现在你惹了一身麻烦
It's been nothing but trouble for you.
你没把我丢在这  是我跟着你来的
You didn't leave me here. I followed you.
你一直是个好奇心强的女孩
You always were a curious girl.
爱丽丝  祝你好运
Good luck, Alice.
那现在怎么办
So what happens now?
任何愿望
Anything.
一切愿望
Everything.
我能许下任何愿望吗
So I can wish for anything I want?
有几个限制条件
There are a few restrictions.
可以说是魔法的法则
The laws of magic, as it were.
-魔法的法则  -是
- Laws of magic? - Yes.
有四条  我不能杀人
There are four of them. I can't kill anyone.
不能让死人复生
I can't bring anything back from the dead.
不能改变历史
I can't change the past.
也不能让任何人坠入爱河
And I can't make anyone fall in love.
合情合理
Reasonable enough.
第三个愿望之后会怎么样
After the third wish, what happens then?
我回到瓶子里
I get returned to my bottle,
然后其他人再次找到我
and then someone else finds me.
所以你的一生
So you spend your entire life--
就是为主人享乐而存在
Serving at the pleasure of my masters.
是的
Yes.
如果我希望
What if I wish...
你能得到自由呢
for your freedom?
已经试过了
I-it's been tried,
结果却是两败俱伤
and it's never gone well for either party.
愿望总是要付出代价的  爱丽丝
Wishes come with a cost, Alice.
许下的愿望越大  承受的后果就越大
The bigger the wish, the greater the consequence.
听起来很危险
Sounds dangerous.
我觉得  你就是喜欢带点危险感的东西
I get the feeling you like a little danger.
你还不知道要许下什么愿望
You're still not sure what to wish for.
也许我们可以
Perhaps we could...
走一走
take a walk.
我可以给你些建议
I can give you some suggestions.
非常乐意
I'd like that very much.
我不得不承认  我喜欢在天上飞
I must admit, I do enjoy the flying.
你一直喜欢飞
You always did.
不论如何  小水
For what it's worth, Sil,
其他的事我也喜欢
I enjoyed some of the other bits as well.
比不上我现在要享受的
Not nearly as much as I'm going to enjoy this.
威尔
Will!
我盼这一天已经很久了
I can't tell you how long I've been waiting for that.
你怎么能
How could you--
相信我  这是他活该
Trust me. He deserved it.
可我们得去救他  他不会游泳
But we have to get him! He can't swim!
抱歉  不能绕路
Sorry. No detours.
见鬼
Oh, bloody hell!
救命
Help!
你对那小仙女做过什么
What did you do to that fairy?
我对她做过什么了
What did I do to her?
她刚把我扔进这该死的湖里
She just tossed me into the bloody lake!
显然你罪有应得
Which you clearly deserved.
现在我们困在荒无人烟的地方
Now we're stuck in the middle of nowhere,
全都怪你伤了一个小仙女的心
all because you broke a fairy's heart.
她一开始就不应该给出她的心
Well, she shouldn't have given it away in the first place.
威尔  没人能控制自己的情感
People can't help falling in love, Will.
能控制
Sure, they can.
只要半夜偷跑出来
You just sneak out in the middle of the night,
穿上裤子  拿上钥匙  一去不回头
grab your trousers, your keys, and don't ever look back.
你怎么会这样
How did you get this way?
-谁这样对你了  -这与我无关  爱丽丝
- Who did this to you? - This isn't about me, Alice.
就算是  我也是坐在家里
If it were, I'd be sat back at home,
开心地看着电视
happily watching the telly.
别问了
Don't ask.
我想告诉你的是
Look, all I'm trying to tell you is,
你的脑中记录着对塞勒斯的记忆
you've got this picture of Cyrus in your mind,
都是一些美好细致的小回忆
these perfect little memories of how things were.
但也许那只是你一厢情愿
But maybe that's just how they were for you.
不是这样的
It wasn't like that.
而且如果你真这么认为
And if you really believe that,
那我们来这干嘛
what are we doing here?
这是你的任务  爱丽丝  不是我的
This is your quest, Alice, not mine.
我是冲着愿望来的
I'm in it for the wish,
就和别的那些寻找精灵的人一样
just like everybody else looking for a genie.
有什么事吗
Is something wrong?
你看起来有些紧张
You seem a little on edge.
抱歉
Sorry.
做精灵就如同通缉犯似的
Being a genie is a lot like being a wanted man.
总是有人在找你
Someone's always after you.
你知道是谁在找你吗
Do you know who that "someone" is?
目前有个叫贾法尔的人
At the moment, a man called Jafar.
他带着一根蛇头魔杖
He carries this staff with the head of a serpent.
如果你看见他
If you ever see him...
怎么了
What?
希望你永远不要遇见他
Well, let's just hope you never do.
他想要什么
What does he want with you?
所有人梦寐以求
What everyone wants.
却得不到的
What they don't have.
你不必因为我而留在外面
You don't have to stay out here on my account.
如果你在瓶子里更安全  那你该...
If you're safe in your bottle, you should--
不  我很长时间
No. This is the closest thing
没有这么接近自由了
I've had to freedom in a long time.
我也一样
I could say the same.
如果你的家就像个囚牢
If your home is such a prison,
为什么你还要回去
why make it your mission to return?
我没别的地方可去了
I have nowhere else to go.
这世界每个角落你都可以去  爱丽丝
You have the whole world, Alice.
我可以带你去
I can show it to you.
你只要许愿就可以了
All you have to do is wish.
但我还有很多问题
But I have more questions.
你还想知道什么
What else would you like to know?
一切
Everything.
你遇见的人  你做过的事
The people you've met, the things you've done--
你斩杀过龙吗
Have you ever slain a dragon?
杀过一次  可我不推荐你做这个
Once. I can't recommend it.
这需要灵巧的剑术
It required some deft swordplay.
我一直都不是很会用剑
I've never been comfortable with a sword.
你一直都不是很会用剑吗
You've never felt comfortable with a sword?
那这么久  你是怎么生存下来的
Then how have you survived here all of this time?
还有别的战斗方法
There's other ways to fight.
而且在仙境里  你只需要
And in wonderland, you just
敢于创造
have to be... creative.
就像这样吗
Like this?
真漂亮
It's beautiful.
而且闻起来真的有玫瑰花香
And it actually smells like a rose.
这是魔法纸
It's magic paper.
是我在旅行中弄到的小东西
A little something I picked up on my travels.
看来你去过很多地方
You've traveled a lot, I take it.
的确  这是跟随诸多主人的代价
Indeed. It's the price of many masters.
我从没在一个地方待过很久
I'm never in one place very long.
他们许下自己的愿望  然后就...
They make their wishes, and then they just...
继续生活
move on.
我知道那种感觉
I'm afraid I know the feeling.
那种被丢下的感觉
I know what it's like to be moved on from.
我不大相信有人会丢下你
I find it hard to imagine anyone wanting to move on from you.
真奇妙
Amazing.
你能教我吗
Can you teach me?
那就教你折纸
An origami lesson shall be yours.
实际上...
Actually...
我是指剑术
I meant the swordplay.
那个精灵的瓶子
The genie's bottle.
你知道它在哪儿
You have knowledge of its whereabouts.
你们才刚刚确立了关系  寒暄就已经省了吗
Dispensing of pleasantries so early on in our relationship?
真悲剧
How tragic.
我们没有什么关系
This is not a relationship,
而且我很忙
and I'm a very busy man.
你一直这么说
So you keep saying.
但在我看来  所有的工作都是我在做
Yet it appears to me that I am the one doing all the work.
是我把爱丽丝重新带回仙境
I brought Alice back to Wonderland,
并找出瓶子藏在哪儿了
and I found out where the bottle is hidden.
在哪儿
Where?
我很愿意告诉你  贾法尔
I'm happy to share that information with you, Jafar.
但首先  我们得谈一谈
But first, I feel like we need a little chat.
我也有想要的东西
I have needs.
要想让我开始下一步的行动
Before I am happy to play another hand in the game,
你得证明你能满足我的需要
I need proof that you can satisfy them.
你需要的  我的姑娘
What you need, my girl...
就是闭嘴
is to be quiet.
你需要的...
What you need...
就是不要动
is to be still.
安静  听从命令
Silent. Follow orders.
最重要的是
Most of all, be grateful
心怀感激  因为我还让你活着
for the air I'm allowing you to breathe.
我们不是合作伙伴
We're not partners.
我什么也不欠你的
I don't owe you anything.
我给过你承诺
I have given you my word,
这就足够了
and that is more than most ever receive.
听明白了吗
Is that clear?
让我来帮帮你
Let me help you with that.
听明白了吗
Is that clear?
告诉我瓶子在哪儿
Tell me where the bottle is.
密草地
Mimsy meadows,
在高耸弦树下
beneath the towering TumTum Tree.
你看
See?
我们合作很愉快嘛
We make a wonderful team.
我们永远也到不了了
We're never gonna make it there.
还有很远的路要走
It's miles and miles away.
的确
True.
有点儿令人灰心  这我承认
This is a bit of a setback, I'll give you that.
但我相信  会找到别的方法的
But I'm sure we'll find another way.
怎么找
How?
给我一分钟
Give me a minute.
两分钟
Two minutes.
我们没有两分钟了  威尔
We don't have two minutes, Will.
我们今天就得到
We need to get there today!
这到底是什么
What the bloody hell was that then?
不知道
I don't know.
这算什么岛
What kind of an island is this?
这不是一个岛
This isn't an island.
什么
What?
抓紧
Hold on tight.
-抓紧  抓什么  -什么都行
- Tight? To what? - Anything.
爱丽丝
Alice!
痒吗
Did that tickle?
海龟
A turtle?
如果你还想要你的脑袋
If you want to keep your head,
那就赶紧带我们去目的地
I suggest you take me where I want to go!
好孩子
Good boy.
现在出发
Now go!
对于不是很会用剑的人来说
For someone who's not comfortable with a sword,
你表现得非常好
you're quite good.
我哪天一定要去弄把剑
I must get one of these someday.
不  这不是一个愿望
No, that's not a wish.
你现在需要做的就是学会用剑
Now all you have to do is learn how to use it.
漂亮  现在握松些
Well done. Now loosen your grip.
你持剑的方式就像个街头混混
You're holding it like a street fighter.
好多了
Better.
你一直学得这么快吗
Have you always been such a quick study?
我不到一周就学会了
I learned how to play Mozart's "Sonata in C"
莫扎特的C大调鸣奏曲
in under a week.
真神奇  怎么学的
Amazing. How?
我妈妈以前常弹  至少别人是这么说的
My mother used to play. Or so I was told.
她在我出生时去世了
She died when I was born.
我想如果我要是能学会弹琴  和她一样
I thought if I learnt to play like her,
就会让我父亲开心
it would make my father happy.
他开心了吗
Did it?
失去了心爱的人
It's hard to be happy again
就很难再开心了
when you've lost someone you love.
抱歉
Sorry.
我不是有意的
I didn't mean to.
没关系
Don't be.
我现在怎么办
What do I do now?
就是你常做的
Same thing you've always done.
随机应变
Be creative.
当对手也富有创造力时
It's hard to be creative
就很难随机应变了
when your opponent's uncommonly creative, too.
我想关键就是
Well, I suppose the trick
永远比对手技高一筹
is to always be smarter than your opponent,
也就是说你要清楚对手是谁
which means you have to know who you're up against.
我会记住的
I'll remember that.
那么  爱丽丝  现在怎么办
So, Alice, what now?
我觉得我熟悉我的对手
I think I know my opponent.
我知道他的弱点
I think I know his weakness.
真的吗
Really?
但愿我没错
I hope so.
看来我是对的
Looks like I was right.
你磨蹭什么呢
What are you waiting for?
我差点被淹死  又险些被素甲鱼吃掉
I nearly drowned and was eaten by a mock turtle.
我就不能休息一下吗
Can I have a moment, please?
不行
Nope.
又是你
You again?
我真高兴你还活着  杰克
I'm actually glad to see you alive, Knave.
怪了  刚才明明是你想杀我
That's strange, since you're the one that tried to kill me.
那是在我得知悬赏你的奖金之前
That was before I heard about the bounty on your head.
看来你把毛虫得罪得不轻啊
Turns out you're in pretty deep to the caterpillar.
好吧  我只是犯了个可怕的错误
Okay, look. I made a horrible mistake.
事实是  你说得没错
The thing is, you were right about everything.
你我之间的事发生后  我感觉糟透了
I felt bloody awful after what happened between us.
即使你有过良心
If you ever had a heart,
现在也早没了
I don't know what happened to it.
话说回来
But then again,
说不定是被你亲爱的安娜斯塔西娅用光了
maybe your precious Anastasia used it all up.
你说得对
You're right.
我不觉得难受
I don't feel terrible.
一点都不觉得
Not even a little bit.
但那是因为我再也没有任何感觉了
But that's because I don't feel much of anything anymore.
你我之间的事就是
So why don't we both agree
我是个彻头彻尾的混蛋  咱们就此分道扬镳
that I'm a right bastard and go our separate ways?
不要把毛虫扯进来
We don't need to bring the caterpillar into this.
我为什么要在乎你的命运
Why should I care about your fate?
大可不必
You shouldn't.
但请关心一下她的命运
But care about hers.
她是个正直的人  她爱的男人也是
She's a decent person, and so is the man that she loves,
在我们说话这会儿  他的生命岌岌可危
whose life is literally hanging in the balance as we speak.
不要让好人为坏人犯下的错误付出代价
Don't make the good guys pay for the bad guys' mistakes.
水仙子  我为所做的一切深感抱歉
I am sorry, Silvermist. For everything.
那你走吧
Be on with you, then.
-真的吗  -离开这里  快走
- Really? - Get out of here. Go.
你是在道歉吗
Was that you apologizing?
我也是会道歉的  别深究了
It happens. Don't dwell on it.
走吧
Come on.
谁是安娜斯塔西娅
So who's Anastasia?
谁也不是
Nobody.
不管怎样  还是谢谢你
Well, in any case, thank you.
早上好
Good morning.
我遇见你后的每个早上都那么美好
All the mornings are good since I've met you.
咱们今天做什么
So what should we do today?
你提到过的那个地方  沸腾之海
You mentioned that place, the Boiling Sea.
-我总想去...  -爱丽丝
- I've always wanted to-- - Alice.
是时候了
I think it's time.
什么时候
For what?
是时候许愿了
For you to make your wishes.
我做错什么了吗
Did I do something wrong?
没有
No.
事实上  我想象不出你会做错任何事
In fact, I can't imagine you ever doing anything wrong.
这就是问题所在
Which is the problem.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我爱上你了  爱丽丝
I'm falling in love with you, Alice.
塞勒斯
Cyrus...
我不能让这种事情发生
I can't allow that to happen.
总有一天  你会许下愿望
Because at some point, you're going to make your wishes
继续自己的生活
and move on with your life.
我又会回到瓶子里
And while I've gotten used to being alone
独自一人度过漫长的岁月
inside this bottle for years at a time,
一想到永恒的时间中将没有你的陪伴
the thought of spending an eternity there without you--
我就觉得难以承受
It's too much for me to bear.
但如果我不许愿
But if I don't make my wishes,
你就永远不用回到瓶子里
you'll never go back inside.
每个人都会许愿
Everyone makes their wishes.
-我不会的  -你现在这么说
- I won't. - You say that now,
但在我无尽的生命历程中
but I've lived countless lifetimes
所有人最终都会许下愿望
and no one has ever not made their wishes.
我为什么要许愿呢
Why would I wish for anything?
我已经拥有了想要的一切
I have everything I could possibly wish for.
你就是我想要的一切  塞勒斯
You are everything I've ever wished for, Cyrus.
如果你不再爱我了呢
What if you change your mind?
我不会的
I won't.
但如果你变心了呢
But what if you do?
你得相信我
You just have to trust me.
咱们做个交易吧
How about we make a deal?
如果你永远不背弃我的话
I'll never move on from you
我也永远不会背弃你
if you never move on from me.
咱们怎么处理这个
What do you propose we do with this?
咱们把它埋起来
We bury it.
找到那个瓶子
Find the bottle.
等等我
Wait for me!
你不能就自己这么跑了
You can't just go running...
什么情况
What is it?
咱们有伴了
We've got company.
抱歉  爱丽丝  咱们来晚了
I'm sorry, Alice. We're too late.
不  时机刚刚好
Actually, we're just in time.
什么意思
What do you mean?
他快挖完了
He's about to finish digging.
让他挖  瓶子不在那
Let him. The bottle's not here.
从来都不在
Never was.
那咱们为什么来这里
Then, um... then--then why are we here?
我要知道对手是谁
I wanted to know who we're up against,
现在我知道了
and now I do.
这就是为什么
So that's why you kept
你把我们的目的地告诉了所有人
telling everybody where we're headed.
仙境里唯一一条可以依靠的法则
The one thing you can count on in wonderland
就是不能信任任何人
is that you can't count on anyone.
真聪明
You are clever.
他叫贾法尔
His name is Jafar.
你认识他吗
Do you know him?
听说过
I know of him.
等等
Wait a second.
你也没告诉我真相
You didn't tell me the bloody truth, either.
也就是说你也不信任我吗
Does that mean you don't trust me?
至少我现在相信你了
If it helps, I do now.
现在你可以和我一起去了
Which is why you're coming with me.
去哪
Where?
去瓶子的真正所在地
To where the bottle is really hidden.
豌豆小路
Passage made of peas.
老虎之塔
Tower of tigers.
风车  就是这里了
The windmill. This is it.
那是蒲公英狮
And there's the Dandelion!
这儿棒极了
These actually aren't half bad.
没人来把你的地标吃了可真是谢天谢地
You're lucky no one came along and ate your bloody landmark.
不
No.
不可能
It's impossible.
瓶子不见了
The bottle, it's gone.
你之前说过的
What you said before--
也许你是对的
maybe you were right.
也许他放弃我了
Maybe he's moved on.
找到她
Find her!
起来
Get up!
站起来  精灵
On your feet, genie.
你想要什么
What do you want?
它在哪里
Where is it?
-什么东西  -你知道是什么  瓶子
- What? - You know what. The bottle.
瓶子在哪里
Where is it?
继续啊  杀了我
Go ahead. Kill me.
我不需要杀死你
I don't have to kill you.
我会杀死她  当着你的面
I'll kill her... in front of you,
除非你立刻告诉我瓶子在哪里
Unless you tell me where the bottle is immediately.
瓶子在我手里
I have it.
今天早晨你给我的建议真不错
Very good advice you gave me this morning.
我想明白了  要想赢得你的尊重
There was I thinking I needed to earn your respect,
我所需要做的不过是强取
when really all I needed to do was to take it.
瓶子在你手里
You have the bottle?
别再小看我了  贾法尔
Stop underestimating me, Jafar.
你的地牢真是不错
Very nice dungeon you have here.
看得出来你很喜欢黑暗
I can really see you enjoy dankness.
这让我想到得告诉你
Remind me to tell you
在身边保留美好之物的重要性
the value of keeping pretty things around.
这里就有一个
There's one.
告诉我瓶子在哪里
Tell me where it is.
游戏规则也该改改了
How about we start with changing the game?
开始启用新规则
Beginning with a new rule.
别再用轻蔑的语气跟我说话
Do not talk down to me anymore!
你瞧  我本打算告诉你瓶子藏在哪儿的
You see, I was planning on telling you where the bottle was hidden.
但我又意识到  我不信任你
And then I realized something. I don't trust you.
而我不信任你的理由就是
And the reason I don't trust you--
我们的关系无法惠及双方
because this relationship is not mutually beneficial.
你手上有所有的王牌  而我一无所有
What with you holding all the cards and me holding nothing.
但现在已不再如此了  是吗  亲爱的
But all that's changed now, hasn't it, darling?
精灵在你的手上
You have the genie...
而瓶子在我的手上
and I have the bottle.
他已经开始新生活了
He's moved on.
这是唯一合理的解释
It's the only thing that makes sense.
在这个世界上  只有塞勒斯和我
Cyrus and I were the only two people in the world
知道这个瓶子的所在
that knew where that bottle was.
或许并非如此
Or you weren't.
你确定你从没有跟别人提起...
Are you positive that you never mentioned--
从没有
Yes!
也许这整件事只是我的一厢情愿
Maybe this whole thing was a fool's errand,
我就是个傻瓜
and I'm the fool.
爱丽丝  我们应该找个藏身处
Alice, we should get some shelter.
这里不安全
It's not safe here.
谁在乎
Who cares?
爱丽丝
Alice?
都还顺利吗
Everything went well then?
非常顺利  谢谢你
Very well, thank you.
那么  接下来
So, then...
怎么了
Yes?
恕我冒昧  女王陛下
All due respect, Your Majesty,
我已经履行了我的义务
I-I fulfilled my obligations.
我超额超质量地完成了我的任务
I-I went above and beyond the call of duty.
没错
It's true.
你的确做到了
Indeed you did.
而您向我承诺过...
And you promised me that if...
承诺就是用来违背的
Promises were made to be broken.
如同我能轻易折断某只
As are the bones of little bunnies
忘记自己正身处危险之中的小兔子的骨头
who forget what they have at stake.
现在  最后再说一遍
Now, for the last time,
在我得到了我所想要的之后
when I get what I want,
你才可以得到你所想要的
you will get what you want.
这个道理有这么难懂吗
Why is it such a difficult concept for everyone?
现在告诉我
Now tell me...
你为何会知道瓶子的真正埋藏地点
how did you really know where that bottle was hidden?
你从没提过
You never did say.
我  我看见了他们
I... I saw them...
在我们埋之前  请记住
Before we do this, understand,
和我在一起的生活不会轻松
life with me will not be easy.
没有你的生活才不轻松
Life without you hasn't been easy.
你需要随时保持警惕
You'll always have to keep one eye over your shoulder.
总会有人对我们虎视眈眈
Someone will always be coming.
你真的相信爱情能够强大到给我们自由吗
Do you truly believe that love is powerful enough to give us our freedom?
我相信我们的爱情可以
I believe ours is.
你相信吗  如果你不信的话...
Do you? Because if you don't--
爱丽丝  我告诉过你了
Alice, I've told you,
我永远不会离开你
I will never leave you.
那你还在等什么
What are you waiting for?
疯狂的小屁孩
Crazy kids.
亲爱的  抱歉  我迟到了
Honey! Sorry I'm late!
拜托你赶快睡觉吧
Please go to sleep.
我睡不着  你睡吧
I can't. You sleep.
你思考得这么大声  我怎么睡得着
How can I sleep if you insist on thinking so loudly?
我很抱歉  爱丽丝
I'm sorry, Alice.
我让你有了这个可怕的想法
I put that terrible idea in your head.
别听我的  爱情
Don't listen to me. Love.
我对此一无所知
I don't know nothing about it.
我觉得你知道
I think you do.
安娜斯塔西娅是谁
Who's Anastasia?
那是个心碎的故事
That... is a tale of heartbreak.
心碎的是你还是她
Yours or hers?
无论是谁  有什么关系吗
Either way, does it matter?
好了  现在你知道了
So there. You got me.
我的确了解爱情
I do know something about love.
但这并不代表你们俩也会这样
But that doesn't mean I'm right about you two.
你相信你们之间是真爱吗  你和塞勒斯
Do you believe that he truly loves you? Cyrus?
我相信
I did.
那就够了
Well, that's good then.
因为如果他真心爱你
Because when somebody truly loves you,
是绝对无法继续新生活的
they can never move on.
我父亲就做到了
My father did.
你说什么
I'm sorry?
他爱我  但他弃我而去开始了新生活
He loved me, and he moved on.
现在历史又重演了
And now it's happening again.
这他妈的是什么鬼东西
What the bloody hell is that?
证明
Proof.
挚爱的爱丽丝
My dearest Alice,
我用了几生几世来遇见你
It took several lifetimes to meet you,
却只用了数秒来爱上你
but only seconds to love you.
此爱永不消逝
And it is a love that cannot be broken.
无法被咒语或剑戟磨灭
Not by a thousand spells or swords.
我对你的心亦永不磨灭
So it is with my heart in your hands...
只求你能应允我的一个愿望
that I ask you to grant me one wish.
离开仙境
Leave Wonderland.
这里不安全
You're not safe here,
你也无法救出我
and you cannot save me.
唯一比我身死更糟的事
The only thing worse than my own demise
便是你是因我而死
would be knowing that I have caused yours.
我恳求你回去
I beg you to go home.
记住  我永远与你同在
And know that I am with you always.
我即是你
Forever thine, forever mine...
塞勒斯
Cyrus.
他还活着
He's alive.
我还以为你深爱着某人的时候
I thought when you truly loved somebody,
是不需要任何证明的
you didn't need any proof.
的确不需要
You don't,
但有证明总是好的
but it's still nice to have.
我将为你而来
仙
境
奇
缘
第一季  第二集
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译  冰蓝  爱卿遛小鸟  Slience
翻译  死跑龙套的  茶炒栗子  如是我闻
校对  米苏  面条打包子
时间轴  冰蓝  萌
时间轴/后期  吉吉
总监  wdjmhs